# PAVIN PANDEY

### Frontend Developer

+91-8286394068
pavinpandey9

✓ pavinpandey9@gmail.com
in pavin-pandey

♦ Thane - 401107♦ portfolio

### SUMMARY

Experienced Frontend Developer with 3 years of expertise in developing user-friendly, adaptive and responsive web applications. Possess solid knowledge of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, complemented by knowledge of modern frameworks like Angular, React, Bootstrap, and Tailwind, with the ability to quickly learn new technologies.

# EDUCATION

Mumbai University

BSc - Computer Science

Grade: A

## SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript

Libraries and Frameworks: Angular, RXJS, React, Redux, Tailwind, Bootstrap

Tools: Git, JIRA, Figma, VS Code

### Experience

### AMK - Frontend Developer

Jul 2023 - Present

- Engineered a visa appointment scanning feature to display appointment details like visa center, appointment status (upcoming or visited), achieving a 96% accuracy rate and significantly enhancing process efficiency.
- Collaborated with back-end developers and designers to integrate third-party services and RESTful APIs to add new functionalities, increasing user interaction by 25%.
- $\bullet$  Created self-contained, reusable components, resulting in a 30% reduction in development time and a 15% increase in team productivity.
- Participate in Agile development processes, including sprint planning, daily stand-ups, and code reviews.

## Testbook Edu Solutions - Frontend Developer

Sep 2022 - May 2023

- Developed and executed front-end strategies, increasing website performance by 15% by implementing optimization techniques such as code minification and troubleshooting with browser developer tools.
- Developed and maintained technical documentation for the front-end codebase, resulting in a 20% reduction in onboarding times for new developers.
- Utilized SEO best practices and techniques to optimize web applications for maximum speed and scalability and improve website performance by 20%.

### Rapid Web Solutions - Jr. Frontend Developer

Aug 2021 - Sep 2022

- Translated complex design mockups into pixel-perfect, interactive user experiences, enhancing customer engagement and driving web traffic.
- Developed responsive, mobile-first interfaces for seamless experiences across multiple devices and platforms, ensuring cross-browser compatibility.
- Implemented version control systems to streamline development projects and ensure code accuracy, cutting the project development time by 25%.

### Sterling Talent Solutions - Specialist

Aug 2017 - Apr 2021

- Addressed client and applicant inquiries for seamless verification processes, ensuring client satisfaction.
- Conducted thorough quality checks and prepared audit reports, resulting in a 20% increase in process efficiency.

#### Concentrix - Practitioner

Jun 2016 - Aug 2017

- Resolved customer queries via email, chat, and call, with high accuracy.
- De-escalated problematic customer concerns, maintaining calm, friendly demeanor.

### PROJECTS

- React Crud App 🗹
- Angular Crud App 🗹

### AWARDS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- Star Performer Award Testbook Edu Solutions
- Rising Star Award Rapid Web Solutions